{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What religious ceremony do the Tai-Ahoms celebrate in honour of their ancestors?",
            "options": [
                "A. Ali-Aye-Lrigang",
                "B. Bhatheli",
                "C. Me-Dam-Me-Phi",
                "D. Chomangkan"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Me-Dam-Me-Phi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following tribes performs Tusu Puja?",
            "options": [
                "A. Mising",
                "B. Karbi",
                "C. Tea Tribe",
                "D. Dimasa"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Mising"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Bash Puja is observed by which of the following community?",
            "options": [
                "A. Karbi",
                "B. Koch Rajbongshi",
                "C. Rabha",
                "D. Boro"
            ],
            "answer": "D. Boro"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following festival is celebrated by the Karbi?",
            "options": [
                "A. Chomangkan",
                "B. Dehal Puja",
                "C. Rongkher",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following festival is celebrated by the Ahoms?",
            "options": [
                "A. Me-Dam-Me-Phi",
                "B. Umpha Puja",
                "C. Somdeo Puja",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Me-Dam-Me-Phi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following festival is celebrated by the Boro community?",
            "options": [
                "A. Bwisagu",
                "B. Kherai",
                "C. Garja",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following festival is celebrated by the tea-community?",
            "options": [
                "A. Tusu Puja",
                "B. Chaita Parv",
                "C. Karam Puja",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following festival is celebrated by the Mising community?",
            "options": [
                "A. Ali-Aye-Lrigang",
                "B. Dobur",
                "C. Parag",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following festival is celebrated by the Tiwa community?",
            "options": [
                "A. Yaling",
                "B. Sogra Misawa",
                "C. Songkhong",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following festival is celebrated by the Rabha community?",
            "options": [
                "A. Hashang Puja",
                "B. Hatasuwani",
                "C. Hathasuni",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "What festival is celebrated by the Deori community?",
            "options": [
                "A. Bohagya Bichu",
                "B. Du Minusi Liduraba",
                "C. Hauniya Puja",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "What festival is celebrated by the Hajong community?",
            "options": [
                "A. Kautokou Puja",
                "B. Kati Gasa",
                "C. Lewatana Bihu",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following festival is celebrated by the Buddhists community?",
            "options": [
                "A. Poisankentai",
                "B. Poilengtai",
                "C. Mykuchumfaitai",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which month the Dehing Patkai festival celebrated?",
            "options": [
                "A. January",
                "B. March",
                "C. April",
                "D. November"
            ],
            "answer": "C. April"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Jonbeel Mela is famous for?",
            "options": [
                "A. For the visit of Gova King to the Fair",
                "B. To get goods at an affordable rate",
                "C. For the prevalence of the barter system",
                "D. For sightseeing"
            ],
            "answer": "C. For the prevalence of the barter system"
        },
        {
            "question": "According to the Yogini tantra, the ancient Kamrup was divided into how many parts?",
            "options": [
                "A. Five",
                "B. Six",
                "C. Four",
                "D. Three"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Five"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first king of Kamrup?",
            "options": [
                "A. Mahiranga Danava",
                "B. Hatakasura",
                "C. Sambarasura",
                "D. Ratanasura"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Mahiranga Danava"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the king of Kamrup contemporary to the Kurukshetra war?",
            "options": [
                "A. Ghataksaura",
                "B. Ratanasura",
                "C. Bhagadatta",
                "D. Bajrapani"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Bhagadatta"
        },
        {
            "question": "Whose son was Bajradatta?",
            "options": [
                "A. Bhagadatta",
                "B. Narkasura",
                "C. Hatakasur",
                "D. Pralambh"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Bhagadatta"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who established the Varman dynasty?",
            "options": [
                "A. Samudravarman",
                "B. Bala Varman",
                "C. Narayanvarman",
                "D. Pushya Varman"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Samudravarman"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the greatest Ruler of the Varman dynasty?",
            "options": [
                "A. Sthitavarman",
                "B. Susthitavarman",
                "C. Supratisthitavarman",
                "D. Bhaskaravarman"
            ],
            "answer": "D. Bhaskaravarman"
        },
        {
            "question": "During the rule of which of the following did the Bhaskarabda era start in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. Pushya Varman",
                "B. Susthitavarman",
                "C. Bhaskaravarman",
                "D. Chandramukhvarman"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Bhaskaravarman"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which king established the Pala dynasty in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. Ratnapala",
                "B. Dharmapala",
                "C. Indrapala",
                "D. Brahmapala"
            ],
            "answer": "B. Dharmapala"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the kingdom established by Shashanka?",
            "options": [
                "A. Banga kingdom",
                "B. Kamata kingdom",
                "C. Gauda kingdom",
                "D. Bidarbha kingdom"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Gauda kingdom"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is correct about Satisadhani?",
            "options": [
                "A. She was the daughter of King Dharmadhwajpal, also known as Dhirnarayan",
                "B. She was the daughter of the ruler of the Chutia dynasty",
                "C. She was married to Nitai from the Chakusara clan",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who established the Koch dynasty?",
            "options": [
                "A. Naranarayan",
                "B. Biswa Singha",
                "C. Shukladhwaj",
                "D. Raghudev Narayan"
            ],
            "answer": "B. Biswa Singha"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was popularly known as Chilarai?",
            "options": [
                "A. Chakradhwaj",
                "B. Jayadhwaj",
                "C. Shukladhwaj",
                "D. None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Chakradhwaj"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who established the Jaintia kingdom?",
            "options": [
                "A. Parbat Ray",
                "B. Burha Parbat Ray",
                "C. Pratap Ray",
                "D. Sundar Ray"
            ],
            "answer": "B. Burha Parbat Ray"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who established the Ahom Empire?",
            "options": [
                "A. Sukhampha",
                "B. Sudangpha",
                "C. Sukhrangpha",
                "D. Sukaphaa"
            ],
            "answer": "D. Sukaphaa"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the ruler of Assam during the battle of Itakhuli?",
            "options": [
                "A. Sulikphaa",
                "B. Supatphaa",
                "C. Sutanphaa",
                "D. Sukhramphaa"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Sulikphaa"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name of the first chief English ruler of Assam after the Yandaboo Treaty?",
            "options": [
                "A. Robertson",
                "B. David Scott",
                "C. Adam White",
                "D. Captain Neuville"
            ],
            "answer": "B. David Scott"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first Assamese person to oppose British rule in 1826?",
            "options": [
                "A. Piyoli Phukan",
                "B. Dutiram Baruah",
                "C. Formud Ali",
                "D. Gomdhar Konwar"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Piyoli Phukan"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year was Piyoli Phukan and Jiuram dulia baruah trapped?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1829",
                "B. 1930",
                "C. 1830",
                "D. 1857"
            ],
            "answer": "C. 1830"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who took the lead in the sepoy rebellion in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. Piyoli Phukan",
                "B. Gomdhar Konwar",
                "C. Maniram Dewan",
                "D. Piyali Baruah"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Maniram Dewan"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Chief Commissioner in Assam introduced the first entrance and scholarships for higher education?",
            "options": [
                "A. Charles Elliot",
                "B. SC Bailey",
                "C. Colonel Kittinger",
                "D. Henry Hopkinson"
            ],
            "answer": "B. SC Bailey"
        },
        {
            "question": "Cotton College was established in 1901 during the time of which British Chief commissioner?",
            "options": [
                "A. William Bard",
                "B. Bemfield Fuller",
                "C. Henry Cotton",
                "D. Charles Freire"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Henry Cotton"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year was the Assam Provincial Congress Committee formed?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1915",
                "B. 1921",
                "C. 1929",
                "D. 1930"
            ],
            "answer": "B. 1921"
        },
        {
            "question": "When did the first elections held during the pre-independence period in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1935",
                "B. 1936",
                "C. 1937",
                "D. 1931"
            ],
            "answer": "A. 1935"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of Assam at the time of pre-independence?",
            "options": [
                "A. Bishnuram Medhi",
                "B. Gopinath Bordoloi",
                "C. Syed Muhammad Saadulla",
                "D. Sarat Chandra Singha"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Syed Muhammad Saadulla"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first Governor of independent Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. Gopinath Bordoloi",
                "B. Fazal Ali",
                "C. Akbar Hydari",
                "D. Bishnu Sahai"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Akbar Hydari"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first Chief Minister of independent Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. Bishnuram Medhi",
                "B. Bimala Prasad Chaliha",
                "C. Gopinath Bordoloi",
                "D. Syed Muhammad Sadulla"
            ],
            "answer": "B. Bimala Prasad Chaliha"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Guwahati University established?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1948",
                "B. 1950",
                "C. 1949",
                "D. 1953"
            ],
            "answer": "C. 1949"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Guwahati High Court established in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1948",
                "B. 1949",
                "C. 1950",
                "D. 1951"
            ],
            "answer": "B. 1949"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the chief minister of Assam after Gopinath Bordoloi?",
            "options": [
                "A. Bimala Prasad Chaliha",
                "B. Sarat Chandra Singha",
                "C. Bishnuram Medhi",
                "D. Golap Borborah"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Bimala Prasad Chaliha"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the below institutions was/were established in Assam in 1948?",
            "options": [
                "A. Assam Agricultural University",
                "B. Assam Veterinary College",
                "C. Guwahati Akashvani Kendra",
                "D. All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "D. All of the above"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the first blind school established in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1955",
                "B. 1952",
                "C. 1951",
                "D. 1957"
            ],
            "answer": "C. 1951"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the first engineering college of Assam established?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1950",
                "B. 1956",
                "C. 1959",
                "D. 1955"
            ],
            "answer": "A. 1950"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Assam Fixation of Ceiling on Landholding Act also popularly known as the Ceiling Act enacted in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1955",
                "B. 1956",
                "C. 1959",
                "D. 1957"
            ],
            "answer": "B. 1956"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many seats were there for in the first Assam Assembly elections held in 1952?",
            "options": [
                "A. 108",
                "B. 105",
                "C. 126",
                "D. 120"
            ],
            "answer": "C. 126"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Namrup fertilizer industry of Assam established?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1955",
                "B. 1962",
                "C. 1965",
                "D. 1963"
            ],
            "answer": "B. 1962"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Bodo language recognized as a medium of education for the Bodo students at the primary school in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1964",
                "B. 1963",
                "C. 1967",
                "D. 1969"
            ],
            "answer": "C. 1967"
        }
    ]
}
